(opening theme music)
(singing in Japanese)
Maki?
The fact is, she's
a total weakling.
She can't even see curses.
She's just a normal person
swinging around cursed tools.
She'll be a
fourth-grade forever.
I don't know why she's
a jujutsu sorcerer at all.
(Utahime claps)
Okay break's over.
(Mai sighs)
[Miwa] I see!
Well, that's a relief!
Stupid Mai! This
woman is no weakling!
(Miwa yells)
She's using a longer weapon,
so I'd like to
close the distance,
but all I can do is
dodge and parry her!
If she were using the blade-
(Miwa grunts)
I would've died twice!
And she's only fourth-grade?
She could easily defeat
second-grade cursed spirits!
(rock music)
[Miwa] And how is she able
to swing such a long staff
in this forest with so
much stuff in the way?
(Miwa yells)
(Miwa grunts)
(water splashes)
(Miwa pants)
(Miwa sighs)
(water splashes)
(rock music)
[Miwa] New Shadow Style,
Simple Domain!
This allows me to attack
anything that enters
the 2.21-meter radius of
my domain on full-auto reflex.
It's released if my feet move
from the point
were I activated it.
Plus, my Quick
Draw is specialized
against head-on attacks.
It's the fastest technique
of the New Shadow School,
wrapping my blade
in cursed energy
while it's in the
sheath to accelerate it.
But I don't think
this'll settle the match!
I still have to create
an opening first!
Iai-koh, huh?
Looks like she has
some tricks, too.
But there's a
difference in our reach.
Rather than hit me,
she wants to knock
away my cursed tool
and create an opening.
-So in that case-
-(weapon breaks)
[Miwa] She broke it?
She's giving up her
reach advantage?
(weapon swings)
[Miwa] She threw it!
(Miwa grunts)
A hidden weapon?
She's trying to close
the gap by using a decoy!
(Miwa grunts)
My legs moved!
But that's okay,
I'll pull back and draw her
in close enough, and then-
(Miwa grunts)
(water splashes)
[Miwa] Aikidou?
What a great move!
Huh?
Pretty nice sword you got here.
Sword stealing?
Give it back?
(music fades out)
(Mei laughs)
What an interesting girl.
You should just go ahead
and promote her to
second-grade already.
Believe me, I feel the same way.
But the Zen'in clan
keeps on interfering.
I wish they would just change
their position and accept her.
(Mei laughs)
I can't understand such
restraint unless it's money.
You're such a material girl.
I'm more concerned about the
way the coverage around Yuuji
keeps cutting out.
Animals can be fickle creatures.
And sharing senses
with them is tiring.
Yeah? I didn't know that.
Which side're you
on anyway, Mei?
Which side?
I'm on the side of
money, of course.
There's no value to anything
that can't be traded for money.
If you can't make money
with it, what good is it?
(Satoru laughs)
[Satoru] Just how much
have you saved up?
I don't know what
the old man's planning,
but I do know he
won't find it that easy
to deal with Yuuji anymore.
(charm catches on fire)
Oh!
They're on the move!
(Curse 10A chitters)
The cursed spirits
released in the area
all have charms on them.
-So when one disappears-
-(curse explodes)
The corresponding charm
here in the viewing area
is extinguished.
Every charm is
extinguished differently
according to the
registered cursed energy.
When the Tokyo school
exorcises one, it burns red.
When the Kyoto school
exorcises one, it burns blue.
Since Maki is here,
charms extinguished
by unregistered energy
burn red as well.
Well, it's one to one.
So how come no one's
paying attention to the game?
Why can't both sides just
try being nice to each other?
I guess they're all
too much like you.
My only problem is you!
[Kiyotaka] For the record,
it was Panda who
took out Mechamaru.
Lucky!
[Nobara] Come down
here, you goddamned witch!
I've come down there
a few times already.
Maybe you oughta
try and catch me!
(intense music)
[Momo] First-year!
(ground explodes)
(Nobara grunts)
[Nobara] Her cursed energy
wind is like a hurricane!
It's full of rocks and branches!
If I drop my guard,
it'll rip my flesh!
(Nobara gasps)
(Nobara grunts)
You dare damage
my precious face?
A scar on the face is a
badge of honor for a man.
Though it's just an
ugly flaw on a woman.
Huh?
You think jujutsu
sorcery is just strength.
[Nobara] That's because it is.
That's only true
for the men, though.
[Nobara] What do you mean?
Even if they're strong,
women have to be cute,
too, or they'll be undervalued.
And of course,
even if they're cute,
they'll still be undervalued,
unless they're also strong.
Do you get it?
They don't demand strength
from female jujutsu sorcerers.
They demand perfection!
And what's worse?
Mai has to fight against demands
that're even more outrageous!
One thing that I do
get is that you are
a pain in the ass!
(Momo slides)
(wind whips)
[Momo] She's only a first-year
and she's already this
accustomed to fighting?
She's still going strong
no matter how
many times I blast her.
That was nothing.
I'm used to getting
knocked around.
[Momo] If I up my output
any further, I might kill her.
No, that's just an excuse.
The real reason I can't
attack her is Inumaki.
(camera shutters)
What is cursed speech?
It just uses the power of words.
It imbues cursed
energy into sound,
so all you have to do
is to protect your brain
and your ears
with cursed energy.
Cursed speech is a
technique specialized
for use against cursed spirits,
and it's nothing to be afraid
of if you know it's coming.
[Momo] Yes, but
if you don't know
whether it's coming or not,
then you're
constantly distracted!
And I'm not used to
protecting the inside of my head
in the first place!
He's such a nuisance,
whether he's here or not!
Done lecturing?
About time!
Even perfection is easy,
compared to what's always
been demanded of Mai!
She's from one of
the three major clans
of elite jujutsu sorcerers!
The Zen'in Clan!
Where perfection's
expected, and demanded.
They say, "Inherit the Zen'in
clan's hereditary technique!"
And any who don't
meet that demand
start their sorcerer
lives as failures.
What's even worse,
women aren't even allowed
to stand at the starting line.
Without the Zen'in clan lineage,
they're not considered
to be real jujutsu sorcerers.
And, if they're not considered
to be jujutsu sorcerers,
they're not even
recognized as people!
She's lived her
entire life scorned
in a family without
a shred of affection.
The suffering Mai went through
to experience what
we all take for granted.
Why don't you try
thinking that over
with that confused
brain of yours?
You have a curse for a friend!
(Momo yells)
Shut up.
You think misfortune is a
free pass to do anything?
What, then?
You're okay with
those who are blessed
getting trash-talked
behind their backs?
That's just like Saori!
I can't stand her!
Regardless of her upbringing!
And I love Maki, who had to
endure the same upbringing!
Have any of you even
bothered to think about
what kind of person the
idiot you're trying to curse is?
What makes you think
any one of us is obligated
to attain perfection, or
such absurd demands?
Is your entire life just a job?
Straw doll-
Hairpin Technique!
(trees shake)
[Momo] This must be why
she kept shooting those nails
that didn't land any hits!
(electronic music)
(Momo grunts)
(Momo sighs)
(Nobara grunts)
You came close, but you
still couldn't reach me!
(Nobara falls)
Wrong!
I reached you, alright!
This is plenty!
[Momo] A bristle from my broom?
She pulled it out just now!
I don't give a damn
about your "men are this"
and "women have to be that!"
You can keep all
that shit to yourself!
I love myself when I'm
pretty and all dressed up!
And I love myself
when I'm kicking ass!
(Nobara grunts)
(hammer strikes)
I am Nobara Kugisaki!
(Momo grunts)
[Momo] I can't control my broom!
[Nobara] If I hit her with
my hammer, I might kill her!
(Momo grunts)
-[Nobara] So- -(Momo gasps)
[Momo] A squeaky hammer?
(Nobara yells)
(Momo shrieks)
(Momo grunts)
(Momo sighs)
Now, one more time!
(bullet strikes)
(Momo gasps)
(wind swooshes)
Just barely within
effective range.
And just in time.
One hell of a shot.
(intense music)
Hello, Momo?
Don't worry, it
was a rubber bullet.
More important,
wasn't that bright light
Mechamaru's Ultimate Cannon?
And now all of a sudden
I can't get a hold of him.
If he felt cornered enough to
use such a powerful technique,
and now he's missing,
then he probably lost
and Panda's still around.
You should get outta there
and go back to
patrolling from the air.
Without you,
we're all in trouble.
Mm.
Hey,
Mai, I, uh-
It's okay, Momo. I understand.
[Momo] Thanks.
What's this?
Aren't you going
to call your friends?
Well, it's fine by me.
I can still take you,
even two-on-one.
There are lots of different
ways to enjoy this, right?
Sure, I could have
everyone beat you together.
But I'm going to
enjoy beating you,
by myself.
You ought to call me "Big Sis,"
little sister.
So, hey. How do
you feel about Maki?
Aaagh, she's gonna hate
it no matter what I say!
Uh, I think she's a smart
and wonderful woman.
Huh?
I'm talking about as a sorcerer.
Oh, really? What a relief!
To be honest,
I still don't know all
that much about jujutsu.
But Maki's really
strong in a fight.
Maybe it's her balance?
Even just the way
she walks is scary!
Don't forget. She's
a fourth-grade.
Huh? Really?
She's from a famous
sorcerer clan family.
But she left them and
so they've been interfering
with her promotion
ever since she left.
Why's a sorcerer family
not accepting of
a sorcerer like her?
They refuse to acknowledge
what they've already rejected
because they're idiots.
Still, if she does
well in the Event,
and Maki's name starts
to become better known,
it's going to be harder for
them to harass her like that.
So let's start by winning
the group battle, you guys!
You have to fight like you're
about to die all over again!
Right.
[Maki] I can hear you, you know.
(Yuuji, Nobara, and Panda gasp)
Jeez.
I should know better
than to let myself
get distracted like that.
(gun clanks)
What're you smiling about?
(gun shoots)
(bullet slices)
(branches swinging)
(gun shoots)
So what if she
hides out of sight?
Are you just trying
to gain distance?
Well, that won't work!
-(sword swings)
-(tree breaks)
[Mai] Shit!
(gun shoots)
(Mai grunts)
[Mai] From below?
I should've known!
Maki has a talent I don't.
So, have you heard?
About Ougi's daughters?
One of them can't
even see curses,
much less use techniques.
Twins are always
a sign of ill fortune.
[Clan Elder] Thank heaven
they're daughters, at least.
I couldn't bear to see an
eldest son as a lowly servant.
(somber music)
Mai? What's the matter with you?
Let's go! Hurry up!
I'm afraid.
[Maki] Afraid of what?
Come on, if we're late
again, we'll get in trouble.
It's them.
Again?
(Maki sighs)
All right, I'll help you out.
Are you ho-o-
[Maki] Come on,
just close your eyes.
(curse warbles)
If you can't see them, it's
like they're not even there.
(Mai whimpers)
[Mai] You always acted
like you had no fear,
and plowed forward
toward your future!
I always hated you for that.
(somber music)
So you're leaving
the clan, Maki?
You seem to have
plenty of servants around.
I doubt you'll miss me at all.
But I do intend to return
someday, Clan Leader.
(Naobito gulps)
(Naobito exhales)
Why would you return?
So I can become the
head of the Zen'in Clan!
(Naobito laughs)
Well, if that's the case,
I'll put you through ordeals
you'll be lucky to survive!
(somber music)
You can do as you please.
[Naobito] And Mai, as well.
Mai's not involved in this.
(somber music)
What a liar.
(sword clangs)
[Mai] I hate you!
(gun shoots)
(bullets fall)
(gun reloads)
(Mai inhales)
(Mai exhales)
(Maki sighs)
(gun shoots)
(footsteps running)
(out-of-tune music)
(gun shoots)
(sword slashes) [Maki]
That was your sixth shot!
I won't let you reload!
[Mai] I hate you.
(gun shoots)
I hate you!
Which is why
I never told you
about my first love,
or about my technique!
[Utahime] "Construction"
uses one's cursed energy
to create matter from nothing.
It differs from
the manifestation
of an innate domain
within the barrier of
a domain expansion.
The matter produced
by Construction
doesn't disappear when
the cursed technique ends.
Because of that, it consumes
a lot of cursed energy,
and puts a heavy
strain on the body.
Creating one bullet a
day, is Mai's maximum.
So she uses a revolver
to create confusion about
how many bullets she has left.
[Mai] I win.
I win!
(Maki grunts)
[Mai] She-
She caught the bullet?
(Maki grunts)
I should never do that
with my bare hands.
(Mai gasps)
(Mai grunts)
(Mai yells)
[Mai] Maki has a talent I don't.
(Mai grunts)
[Mai] Like Mechamaru,
she has a Heavenly Pact,
but hers is somehow different.
Normally, she would have been
born with a cursed technique.
(Maki grunts)
(Mai grunts)
[Mai] But in exchange for that,
she was granted
superhuman physical abilities.
(Mai sighs)
[Mai] The Zen'in clan
would never acknowledge it.
That this was a talent.
(Mai grunts)
[Mai] That I lacked!
Well, what now?
Is this settled, then?
Why?
Why did you leave the clan?
Come on! You know
the answer to that!
You joined Jujutsu High, too!
Wrong!
-(Maki gasps)
-(Mai sobs)
I never wanted to
be a jujutsu sorcerer!
It's all your fault!
Because you tried
so hard to be one,
I was forced to follow
in your footsteps!
I'm so sick of facing
all these scary things!
What was so awful about being
ordered around back home?
We could have just
done a few chores,
and lived like
everyone else does!
(Mai sobs)
Why couldn't you have
just stayed and been satisfied
down at the bottom with me?
(sad music)
Because,
I would have hated
myself if I had done that.
That's why.
I'm sorry.
(Mai sobs)
(sad music)
[Mai] Big sister! Don't let go!
[Maki] I won't let go.
[Mai] You never will?
[Maki] Jeez, give it a rest.
[Mai] Never leave me behind.
[Maki] Of course I won't.
After all, we're sisters.
(piano music)
[Mai] What a liar.
I hate you.
(closing theme music)
(singing in Japanese)
[Miwa, Momo,
and Mai] Juju Stroll!
(bored music)
[Miwa] I'm so hungry.
Fortunately, I think my left
over edamame from lunch
is still in the fridge.
(Momo and Mai chewing)
-Hm?
(Miwa grunts)
(Momo chewing)
(Momo swallows)
Sorry.
[Miwa] You could at least
try to look a little guilty!
[Momo] As a token of
my apology, have this.
(Miwa sighs) No,
I'm not interested
in late-night cup ramen.
(Momo laughs)
How about this?
Nishimiya-style
Seafood Cup Ramen!
Step one, use scissors to
chop up hot chili peppers
into the seafood cup ramen!
Two: Fill the container
halfway with milk.
Three: Add hot water
up to the line inside!
Since we're using milk, make
sure the water's boiling hot!
(Miwa slurps)
(Miwa gasps)
[Miwa] This is good!
It's really good!
[Momo] Right?
[Mai] Maybe I'll
have it next time, too.
Why didn't you eat this?
Instead of taking my edamame.
(Miwa slurps)
Well, you still pay the price
for late-night cup
ramen the next day.
Mm-hm, mm-hm.
(intense rock music)